<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-12-05T13:17:06+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Zhanchao Yu</title><entry><title type="html">独立写作让步段的写法</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/toefl-IW-concession/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="独立写作让步段的写法" /><published>2016-12-05T09:45:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-05T09:45:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/toefl-IW-concession</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/toefl-IW-concession/">&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;相信很多同学目前在写独立写作的时候采用的依然是经典的五段式，中间两个理由段外加一个让步的形式。让步的作用说的直白一点就是防止我们找不到第三个理由没话写，毕竟每个题目都找三个理由真的不是那么容易，很多同学都是瞎凑。当然啦，有一个让步也显得我们的文章的论证更加完整一些。下面咱们通过几个实例来看看让步段到底该咋写。希望大家把让步的套路搞明白之后，最好能记住一套，并且学会如何针对不同题目进行更改，这样一来考场上就能节省大量的时间。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;让步段1&quot;&gt;让步段1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students can use their mobile phones to surf on the Internet or listen to the music while doing their homework.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, some students claim that listening to music or surfing online can reduce the anxiety and tension while doing homework, but what you may not know is that people’s sub-consciousness is actually distracted, which not only slows down the progress of the work but also burdens their nerves. Hence, the real way to relax your mind is to kick off your shoes, sit back and listen to light or classical music after having finished the entire task rather than during the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本题其实是一个典型的一元素的题目，这个元素就是能否看手机，我们可以把这个元素看成 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;, 文章结构就是先说 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; 的两个坏处，&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a1- a2-&lt;/code&gt;, 然后在让步的时候说 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a+&lt;/code&gt;，但是由于题目的立场是反对，所有让步可以以 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a+&lt;/code&gt; 开始，但是最后以 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a-&lt;/code&gt; 结束，否则就会对自己的立场有一定的削弱。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;让步段1的示范&quot;&gt;让步段1的示范&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is important for the government to allocate money on beautiful things, not just for things that are practical. [2014年5月24日]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, some &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; claim that &lt;em&gt;spending money on beautiful things can satisfy people’s higher level needs&lt;/em&gt;, but what you may not know is that &lt;em&gt;the satisfaction of residents’ most basic needs might be compromised&lt;/em&gt;, which not only &lt;em&gt;takes a heavy toll on their living conditions&lt;/em&gt; but also &lt;em&gt;poses a major threat to the government with tight budget&lt;/em&gt;. Hence, &lt;em&gt;there is no better way for a country to achieve successful development than to devote its budgets to practical needs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本题是一个两元素比较类的题目，元素 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; 是美丽的东西，元素 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; 是实际的东西，而立场是支持 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&amp;gt;a&lt;/code&gt;，所以让步的时候我们就写 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a+ a- b+&lt;/code&gt; 从说 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; 的好处过渡到 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; 好。这里面有几个表达希望大家注意一下。主语从句结合&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;not only but also&lt;/code&gt; 的结构：&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;what you may not know is that..., which not only ... but also ....&lt;/code&gt;。以及 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;there is no better way for sb to do sth than to do sth&lt;/code&gt; 。还有 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a take a heavy toll on b and a pose a major threat to b&lt;/code&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;让步段2&quot;&gt;让步段2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Students can benefit from student organization and club activities as much as from their academic studies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, academic study is of vital importance to every student, for it provides the basic and systematic knowledge to which we cannot be blind. However, to emphasize the importance of academic study does not mean that student organizations and club activities are dispensable. One who devotes himself to academic study without paying any attention to extra-curricular activities stands a fair chance to become a nerd with high IQ but low EQ, which is not an ideal case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本题是一个经典的 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a=b&lt;/code&gt; 的题目，立场是支持 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&amp;gt;b&lt;/code&gt; 然后文章结构依然是 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a1+ a2+ b+&lt;/code&gt; 两个理由一个让步的形式。让步的时候 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b+ b- a+&lt;/code&gt; 的套路。这里面有些表达很不错，比如：&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a is of vital importance to b&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;be blind to sth&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;to emphasize the importance of a does not mean that b is dispensable&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;stand a fair chance to do sth&lt;/code&gt;。这些表达希望大家重点记一下，然后融入到自己的让步段的模板里面。几个让步稍微融合一下就可以避免跟别人撞车了。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;让步段2的示范&quot;&gt;让步段2的示范&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visiting a museum is the best way to learn about a country.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, &lt;em&gt;paying a visit to a museum&lt;/em&gt; is of vital importance to &lt;em&gt;learning about a country&lt;/em&gt;, for it provides the basic and systematic knowledge &lt;em&gt;related to the country’s history&lt;/em&gt; to which we cannot be blind. However, to emphasize the importance of &lt;em&gt;museums&lt;/em&gt; does not mean that &lt;em&gt;other ways of getting to a country are of lesser importance&lt;/em&gt;. One who devotes himself to &lt;em&gt;visiting museums&lt;/em&gt; without paying any attention to &lt;em&gt;other ways&lt;/em&gt; stands a fair chance to &lt;em&gt;lose sight of a country’s present magnificence&lt;/em&gt;, which is not an ideal case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本题是一个多元素的题目，翻译过来就是 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&amp;gt;b a&amp;gt;c a&amp;gt;d ... a&amp;gt;n&lt;/code&gt;， 我们的立场是不同意，所以最好找两个不等式来证明他们是不成立的，比如：&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&amp;gt;a c&amp;gt;a&lt;/code&gt;。我们可以写上网这个方式很好啊，另外交友也是一个不错的方式啊。让步承认博物馆有好处，可以让我们了解一个国家的历史，但是如果认为其他方式不如它重要的话很可能不能够了解国家现在的成就，这就不好了。这里面又出现了两个新的短语，&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lose sight of = be blind to&lt;/code&gt; 还有 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;be of lesser importance&lt;/code&gt; 跟 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;be of vital importance&lt;/code&gt; 正好相反。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;让步段3&quot;&gt;让步段3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you agree or disagree: governments should spend more money in sponsoring arts than in athletics.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, the significance of arts cannot be overlooked; building up an artistic atmosphere is conducive to refining people’s artistic taste. If a society is artistically cultivated, hardly would its people’s souls be corrupted by materialism. However, compared with arts, athletics is more fundamental, i.e., without good health, people will not be able to make any great achievements including those in the area of arts. Thus, the vital importance of athletics is self-evident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本题是一个两元素的题目，两个元素分别是艺术和体育，&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&amp;gt;b&lt;/code&gt;。而本题的立场是支持 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&amp;gt;a&lt;/code&gt;。所以文章的结构是 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b1+ b2+ a+&lt;/code&gt;。让步的时候依然是 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a+ b+&lt;/code&gt; 的结构。这里面涉及到的比较不错的表达有：&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;the significance of a cannot be overlooked&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;be conducive to&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;the vital importance of b is self-evident&lt;/code&gt;, 以及倒装句 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;hardly would its people's souls be corrupted by materialism&lt;/code&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;让步段3的示范&quot;&gt;让步段3的示范&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? People who have learned many different skills are more likely to succeed than those who focus on learning only one skill. [2014年2月22日]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, the significance of &lt;em&gt;being versatile&lt;/em&gt; cannot be overlooked since it is conducive to &lt;em&gt;increasing one’s competitive advantage in the workplace&lt;/em&gt;. If &lt;em&gt;an individual has multiple skills&lt;/em&gt;, hardly would &lt;em&gt;he or she be outstripped by others&lt;/em&gt;. However, compared with &lt;em&gt;learning a variety of skills&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;zeroing in on one skill&lt;/em&gt; is more fundamental without which people will not be able to make any great achievements. Thus, the vital importance of &lt;em&gt;concentrating on one skill&lt;/em&gt; is self-evident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本题也是一个两元素的题目，我们只要将模板中的相应位置进行合理的替换即可。替换的时候尽量用一些同义词或者短语来避免重复。本段中也有几个不错的表达，比如：&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;increase one's competitive advantage&lt;/code&gt; 以及 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;be outstripped by = be eclipsed by&lt;/code&gt; 还有 &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;zero in on = focus on&lt;/code&gt;等等。希望大家注意总结哈。&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作让步段" /><summary type="html">相信很多同学目前在写独立写作的时候采用的依然是经典的五段式，中间两个理由段外加一个让步的形式。让步的作用说的直白一点就是防止我们找不到第三个理由没话写，毕竟每个题目都找三个理由真的不是那么容易，很多同学都是瞎凑。当然啦，有一个让步也显得我们的文章的论证更加完整一些。下面咱们通过几个实例来看看让步段到底该咋写。希望大家把让步的套路搞明白之后，最好能记住一套，并且学会如何针对不同题目进行更改，这样一来考场上就能节省大量的时间。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">独立写作开头的写法</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/toefl-IW-intro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="独立写作开头的写法" /><published>2016-12-04T09:37:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-04T09:37:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/toefl-IW-intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/toefl-IW-intro/">&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;很多同学比较纠结，有的可能是压根不知道写啥，还有的可能是特别想写的很出彩，不敢轻易下笔。其实开头最重要的就是要亮明自己的立场，别的都是次要的，所以我们一定要在考前准备好现成的开头，并且搞清楚如何针对不同的题目进行调整，保证不论见到任何题目都能够在2-3分钟之内把开头准确的砸上去。千万不要担心开头背一个通用的模板会影响自己的成绩。根据以往的出分来看，可以放心的告诉大家，考30分的同学开头也是使用的模板，而且并不复杂。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;开头1&quot;&gt;开头1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Recently an interesting question has been attached much concern to: is there any correlation between cleaning one’s room and success? Answers vary from one person to another. Some claim that students keeping their rooms neat and organized are more likely to be successful, while others oppose the idea that cleaning up the room has something to do with success. To my way of thinking, students who have the habit of keeping their rooms clean and tidy are more inclined to succeed than those who do not. My viewpoint is based on the following reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;这是一个非常经典的开头，包括&lt;strong&gt;背景+争议+立场&lt;/strong&gt;。背景是通过 &lt;em&gt;Recently an interesting question has been attached much concern to&lt;/em&gt; 这个句型来引出，意为近来一个有趣的问题得到了很多的关注。紧接着通过答案因人而异 &lt;em&gt;Answers vary from one person to another&lt;/em&gt; 引出争议。接下来通过&lt;em&gt;Some claim&lt;/em&gt;以及&lt;em&gt;while others oppose the idea&lt;/em&gt;阐述具体的不同的观点是什么。最后通过&lt;em&gt;To my way of thinking&lt;/em&gt;来引出自己的观点，并且利用&lt;em&gt;My viewpoint is based on the following reasons&lt;/em&gt;来承上启下。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;开头1的示范&quot;&gt;开头1的示范&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nowadays people are more willing to help others who they do not know (for example giving food or clothing) than they were in the past. [2016年12月3日考题]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently an interesting question has been attached much concern to: &lt;em&gt;are people nowadays more willing to help others&lt;/em&gt; [1]? Answers vary from one person to another. Some claim that &lt;em&gt;people at present are more likely to lend a hand to others&lt;/em&gt; [2], while others oppose the idea. To my way of thinking, &lt;em&gt;I am inclined to agree with the former or the latter&lt;/em&gt; [3]. My viewpoint is based on the following reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;首先在1空和2空我们对题目进行转述，在第3空我们为了避免对题目进行再一次的转述，我们可以直接用 &lt;em&gt;the former or the latter&lt;/em&gt; 这样的表达来亮明自己的立场，毕竟不是每个人都能把题目很快的而且还很好的转述三次的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is easier to become an educated person today than it was in the past？[2016年11月26日考题]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently an interesting question has been attached much concern to: &lt;em&gt;is it easier for people today to become educated than in the old days？&lt;/em&gt;  [1] Answers vary from one person to another. Some claim that &lt;em&gt;receiving an education of higher quality has been becoming much easier not only because of economic boom but also because of the advancement in technology,&lt;/em&gt; [2] while others oppose the idea. To my way of thinking, &lt;em&gt;I am inclined to agree with the former or the latter.&lt;/em&gt; [3] My viewpoint is based on the following reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1空我们依然是将题目变成了一个一般疑问句，其实就是调整一下语序。这个可操作性还是很强的。第2空这次写的稍微复杂一点点，不仅对题目进行了转述，也顺便给出了正文中会涉及到的两个原因。给出原因的时候我们用&lt;em&gt;not only because of A but also of B&lt;/em&gt; 的结构，正好对应中间的两个主体段的理由。第三空不变，依然是利用&lt;em&gt;the former or the latter 表明自己的立场&lt;/em&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;开头2&quot;&gt;开头2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As is known to all, arts and athletics play irreplaceable and indispensable roles in people’s life for the former nurtures a sound mind while the latter guarantees a sound body. And recently there has been a heated debate on whether arts or athletics should be allocated more financial funds to. This debate divides people into two camps with opposite opinions, and as far as I’m concerned, athletics deserves more funding from government than arts does due to its greater significance. My reasons and examples are given below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;跟开头1类似，这个也是一个&lt;strong&gt;背景+争议+立场&lt;/strong&gt;的开头，只是表达和开头1相比有所变化而已。首先我们第一句话可以利用这样的句式来引入背景：&lt;em&gt;A and B  play irreplaceable and indispensable roles in people’s life for the former A的好处 while the latter B的好处。&lt;/em&gt; 紧接着我们通过 &lt;em&gt;Recently there has been a heated debate on whether&lt;/em&gt; 来引出题目。接下来利用 &lt;em&gt;This debate divides people into two camps with opposite opinions&lt;/em&gt; 来引出争议。最后通过 &lt;em&gt;as far as I’m concerned&lt;/em&gt;  亮明自己的立场，并且利用 &lt;em&gt;My reasons and examples are given below.&lt;/em&gt; 过渡到正文。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;开头2的示范&quot;&gt;开头2的示范&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Governments should focus more on preservation of environment rather than economic development. [2009年3月22日]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is known to all,  &lt;em&gt;economy and environment&lt;/em&gt; play irreplaceable and indispensable roles in people’s life for the former &lt;em&gt;ensures a decent life&lt;/em&gt; while the latter &lt;em&gt;guarantees a sound body&lt;/em&gt;. And recently there has been a heated debate on whether &lt;em&gt;economy or environment&lt;/em&gt; should be allocated more financial funds to. This debate divides people into two camps with opposite opinions, and as far as I’m concerned, &lt;em&gt;environment&lt;/em&gt; deserves more funding from government than economy does due to its greater significance. My reasons and examples are given below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;本题在改写的时候比较简单，我们只需要把 &lt;em&gt;athletics&lt;/em&gt; 换成 &lt;em&gt;economy&lt;/em&gt; 把 &lt;em&gt;arts&lt;/em&gt; 换成 &lt;em&gt;environment&lt;/em&gt; 即可，至于两者的好处如果需要调整的话也得进行相应的变化。毕竟我们不能说经济滋养健康的心灵。在套现成的东西的时候大家一定要把每一个该换的地方都换掉，千万不要搞出笑话。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do you agree or disagree, it is a waste of money for government to fund space travel. [2015年10月11日]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is known to all,  &lt;em&gt;space technology&lt;/em&gt; play irreplaceable and indispensable roles in &lt;em&gt;a country’s successful development&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;em&gt;a country’s competitiveness in space exploration represents its national power&lt;/em&gt;. And recently there has been a heated debate on whether &lt;em&gt;space travel&lt;/em&gt; should be allocated financial funds to. This debate divides people into two camps with opposite opinions, and as far as I’m concerned, &lt;em&gt;the exploration of outer space&lt;/em&gt; deserves the funding from government due to its &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; significance. My reasons and examples are given below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;由于开头涉及到两个元素而本题只有一个元素，所以在改写的时候我们要去掉一个，同时也要去掉所有关于比较的部分，比如第一句我们去掉了 &lt;em&gt;the former and the the latter&lt;/em&gt;，而后面我们也去掉了有 &lt;em&gt;than&lt;/em&gt; 以及 &lt;em&gt;er&lt;/em&gt; 的表达。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;看了咱们的开头的讲解以及示范之后相信大家对于开头部分应该比较自信了，接下来强烈建议大家花点儿心思把这两个开头背下来。当然啦，挑一个背也是可以的。最重要的多找几个题目进行套用练习，确保自己会针对不同题目进行更改。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;练习题目&quot;&gt;练习题目&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;考试日期&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;考试题目&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2007年10月28日&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Teachers should be paid according to the performance of their students.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2011年12月18日&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Do you think government should spend money on building new houses or preserving historic buildings?&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2012年7月15日&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;It is important for the government to allocate money on beautiful things, not just for things that are practical.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2012年9月2日&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Do you agree or disagree with the statement: competition with friends usually have negative effect on friendship?&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2012年9月8日&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Do you agree or disagree with the following statement ? The advice from the grandparents is of no use to their grandchildren because the world has changed a lot over the past 50 years.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作开头" /><summary type="html">很多同学比较纠结，有的可能是压根不知道写啥，还有的可能是特别想写的很出彩，不敢轻易下笔。其实开头最重要的就是要亮明自己的立场，别的都是次要的，所以我们一定要在考前准备好现成的开头，并且搞清楚如何针对不同的题目进行调整，保证不论见到任何题目都能够在2-3分钟之内把开头准确的砸上去。千万不要担心开头背一个通用的模板会影响自己的成绩。根据以往的出分来看，可以放心的告诉大家，考30分的同学开头也是使用的模板，而且并不复杂。</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">12月3日写作考后分析</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/after-test-analysis-1203/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="12月3日写作考后分析" /><published>2016-12-03T14:34:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-03T14:34:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/after-test-analysis-1203</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/after-test-analysis-1203/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;独立写作&quot;&gt;独立写作&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Nowadays people are more willing to help others who they do not know (for example giving food or clothing) than they were in the past.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;话题：社会类&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;题型：一元素比较类&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;重复：2013年1月26日[！历年真题串讲必看！]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一边倒&lt;/strong&gt; 今天竟然跟上次一样又是一个今昔对比的题目。如果我们&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;一边倒&lt;/code&gt;的话，完全可以考虑不同意，首先套上&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;压力的段子&lt;/code&gt;，现在人压力大，当然不愿意帮助别人。除了压力大之外，现在这个社会蛇少最基本的信任，也是一个非常重要的原因，这个可以套&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;广告的段子&lt;/code&gt;。再次，我们还可以写现在媒体都在关注名人的私生活，并没有起到合理的导向作用，从而套上&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;媒体的段子&lt;/code&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;分类&lt;/strong&gt; 凡是今昔对比的题目在分类的时候我们的思路都是类似的，都可以&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;按照国家和地区的发展水平&lt;/code&gt;来分，条件好的地方自然愿意，毕竟有钱、毕竟受教育程度高、毕竟科技先进；然而，条件比较差的地方这些东西都没有明显的改善，不可能存在比过去更愿意的情况。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;压力的段子-记忆复写第6篇&quot;&gt;压力的段子 [记忆复写第6篇]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Firstly, it is high time that government arouse people’s awareness of the importance of physical soundness. Along with the acceleration of social development, people, especially young people, are confronted with unprecedentedly fierce competition. They need to work very hard to guarantee a decent life, which causes them way heavier pressures than before. Under such circumstances, most of them are prone to be caught in a sub-healthy state. Given that it is governments’ responsibilities to improve citizens’ health condition, government should increase access to public exercise equipment in the neighborhood and raise people’s awareness of the importance of doing exercises regularly through mass media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;广告的段子记忆复写第29篇&quot;&gt;广告的段子[记忆复写第29篇]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Another case in point falls into the field of education and training industry. In lack of strict supervision from the government, some training schools in China have always been misleading their customers. For the expansion of enrolment, they tend to claim that after taking a certain number of courses, any student will achieve high scores required to enter universities. In fact, such statement is ridiculous for it fails to consider each individual’s situation. In other words, nobody can be guaranteed that he or she is sure to succeed in an exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;广告的段子记忆复写第29篇-1&quot;&gt;广告的段子[记忆复写第29篇]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, it is not reasonable to criticize the mass media, including television, newspapers, magazines and so forth, for its excessive exposure on the personal lives of famous people. In fact, it is the public, to a large extent, rather than the mass media, that is paying too much attention on celebrities’ personal lives. This phenomenon is well interpreted with the fact that many people will spare time to gossip about famous people such as actors, athletes and rock stars. Meanwhile, since most organizations of mass media industry are audience-oriented and mostly driven by business motivation, television program producers, as well as columnists and writers are always aware of what the public want to see, and thus tend to expose famous people’s anecdotes in order to pander to tastes of the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;备考建议&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;独立部分无非就是没思路、写不顺、写不对三个问题，没思路的一定要考前多看看历年真题串讲，最近大部分都是之前考过的旧题。多看串讲一方面可能遇到原题，另一方面确保找思路快啊；至于写不顺或者写不对的同学，那就考前多记段子，自己写不顺、写不对就少写呗，我用别人的总不至于出问题了吧。但提醒大家，用别人的东西一定要首先记准，其次别忘了扣题，千万不要得意忘形。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;综合写作&quot;&gt;综合写作&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;总体观点&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vampire squid 不会吃 marine snow 一些海洋里面的 debris&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;阅读部分&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;marine snow 在海底。而海底氧气少，Vampire squid 缺乏氧气没法生存&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vampire squid 捕食的时候 collect on arm 然后 bring the food to eat，需要保持一个某一个姿势，容易被 predator 发现&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;和 Vampire squid 同一个物种的其他生物不吃 marine snow，而是以捕食活物为生，所以它也应该是类似情况&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;听力部分&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;追猎物的时候需要氧气，而 Vampire squid 不用 chase prey，所以不需要太多的氧气&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;深海中 Vampire squid 皮肤比较暗，不容易被发现；而且即使被发现，它也会突然变亮，吓跑predator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;吃 marine snow 的话不会跟同种别的生物竞争，他们反而更容易获得食物&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;分析&lt;/strong&gt; 这又是一个非常经典的&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;理论证明题&lt;/code&gt;，此类题目无非就是从&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;证据本身或者从推理的角度&lt;/code&gt;来进行反驳，比如第一个点，听力承认了阅读给的证据是对的，但是指出阅读考虑的比较片面的地方，确实需要氧气但并不是一直需要那么多；第二个点直接就攻击证据本身，阅读说容易发现，而听力针锋相对，并且给出了进一步的证据。思路就是首先阅读的不对，其次即使你说的对，也不是事儿；第三个点就是一个极其典型的错误的横向类比，大家只要看到作者试图通过一个做法适用于A推出也试用于B的话，肯定就是这个错误。听力必然会给出二者的不同点。而正是这些不同点导致阅读的说法是有问题的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作真题" /><summary type="html">独立写作</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2012年大陆独立写作题目整理</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2012/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2012年大陆独立写作题目整理" /><published>2016-12-01T18:49:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T18:49:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2012</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2012/">&lt;p&gt;2012年1月14日     All school teachers should be required to take courses every five years to update their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年2月5日     Some people think we should follow our dreams, even if the dreams are ambitious. But other people think that we should focus on realistic goals. Which do you agree?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年2月11日     Agree or disagree, talented people’s leadership is born by natural and can’t be learned by people, agree or disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年2月17日     Some prefer buy new technological devices; others having them when they are well-adopted. which do you prefer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年2月24日     Agree or disagree, people who cannot accept others’ criticism cannot achieve success as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年2月25日     Can two people be good friends if one person has more money than the other?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年2月4日     Are the employees who always try to find new ways to solve problems more valuable than those who simply follow the orders?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年3月10日     If you need to discuss upsetting and controversial issues with others, you will use email or text messaging, or telephone or voice messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年3月18日     There is never a good reason to be impolite or rude to another people, what do you think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年3月24日     Agree or disagree, if parents want their children to perform well in school，they should limit the hours that their children spend watching TV．&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年4月14日     Agree or disagree, a job with more vacation time is better than a job with high salary but less vacation time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年4月22日     Should school focus more on purchasing new equipments or recruiting good teachers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年4月28日     People should know about events happening around world even if they have little influence on their daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年5月12日     Agree or disagree, it is better to choose a university whose graduates have good job opportunities than a university who has famous professors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年5月20日     Agree or disagree, the way of a person’s dress is an indication of his or her personality or character?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年5月26日     Agree or disagree, teachers in the past had more influences on the youth than teachers at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年6月9日     Do you agree or disagree? It is often not a good thing for people to move to a new town or a new country because they will lose their friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年6月17日     Which of the following do you agree with? Parents should help children to do their work or they should encourage children to do their work independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年6月30日     The best way to learn about a foreign country is to read the newspapers and magazines of that country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年7月14日     Agree or disagree, it is better for your friend to ask you for help (suppose you are good at the subject) than to turn to a tutor when he finds it hard to pass an examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年7月15日     It is important for the government to allocate money on beautiful things, not just for things that are practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年7月22日     People can take care of their family members better when they live in big cities than in the countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年7月28日     Some jobs pay a high salaries to employees but require them live far away from their family and friends. Some jobs pay low salary but allow employees to be closer their family and friends. Which job do prefer? And why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年8月19日     Agree or disagree, car has had a greater effect on the society than the airplane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年8月26日     Agree or disagree, the opinions of celebrities, such as famous entertainers and athletes, are more important to younger people than to older people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年8月26日     Parents should allow children to make mistakes and let them learn from their own mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年9月2日     Do you agree or disagree with the statement: competition with friends usually have negative effect on friendship?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年9月8日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement ? The advice from the grandparents is of no use to their grandchildren because the world has changed a lot over the past 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年9月16日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement: The most important investment for a big company is to improve the efficiency and proficiency of its employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年9月20日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? Students are more interested in politics today than before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年9月22日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement. Although science and technology will continue to improve, the most significant improvement for the quality of people’s lives have already taken place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年9月23日     Do you agree or disagree: In order to succeed in a new job, the ability to adapt or adjust to a changing condition or circumstance is more important than having excellent knowledge of the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年10月13日     Do you agree or disagree with the statement: Nowadays，it’s much easier to succeed without assistance from one’s family than it was in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年10月19日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? Reading a student does on his/her own is as important as, or even more important than reading a student does because it is assigned by teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年10月27日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? The most important problems affecting our society today could be solved within our lifetime.Use specific reasons to support your answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年10月28日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? Governments and corporations should share all of their scientific discoveries with the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年11月2日     Out of the following three things, which one would you prefer to regulate in order to improve your health? 1）The kind of food you eat 2）The amount of exercise 3）The amount of stress in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年11月10日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? It is the best way for teachers to make students more interested in a subject by explaining to them that this subject will help them in their life outside of the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年11月18日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement: The main role of a university professor is to educate students rather than to do research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年11月24日     It is easier to become an educated person than it was in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年12月2日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? Movies and televisions have more positive effects on the young people than negative effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年12月8日     Patience is usually not a good strategy. We should take action now rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012年12月22日     A friend who is intelligent is much than a fiend with a good sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作真题" /><summary type="html">2012年1月14日     All school teachers should be required to take courses every five years to update their knowledge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2011年大陆独立写作题目整理</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2011/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2011年大陆独立写作题目整理" /><published>2016-12-01T18:49:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T18:49:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2011</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2011/">&lt;p&gt;2011年1月8日     Agree or disagree, the food we ate in the past was healthier than the food today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年1月22日     Agree or disagree,  in order to celebrate major events, it`s better to organize big party with lots of people than have a small party that only close friends and relatives are invited?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年1月30日     Agree or disagree,  the world is changing so quickly that people now are less happy or less satisfied than in the past ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年2月12日     Agree or disagree, in the busy and crowded world, we should never expect people to be polite to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年2月20日     Agree or disagree, If the people move out of the native village or town is happier and more successful than the people who stay in native village or town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年2月26日     Young people today have no influence on the important decisions about the future of the society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年3月12日     Agree or disagree, people should buy things made by their own country ,even if things of other countries may cost less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年3月13日     Agree or disagree, children should spend most of their time on study and play, and they don’ t need to do housework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年3月20日     People will feel happier if they have fewer possessions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年3月26日     Agree or disagree, young people should try different jobs before they decide which job or career they will do in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年4月23日     Agree or disagree, a job with more vacation time is better than a job with high salary but less vacation time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年5月14日     Agree or disagree, in the past, it was easier for people to identify what types of career or job would lead to a secure, successful future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年5月28日     Agree or disagree, the way of a person’s dress is an indication of his or her personality or character?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年5月29日     Agree or disagree, it is easier to be a success in the past than today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年6月11日     Do you think the concern of environment issues in various countries can actually alleviate the environmental problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年6月19日     Agree or disagree, high school students should take some basic economy courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年6月25日     Agree or disagree, movies and televisions should always show audience good people are being rewarded and bad people are being punished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年7月9日     Do you agree that people should have hobbies and do physical activities that are very different from one’s work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年7月23日     Do you think it is more effective to work as a group than work independently?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年8月13日     Agree or disagree，the personal and work-related challenges we face now are different from those our parents and grandparents faced when they were young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年8月21日     For successful development of a country, should a government focus its budget more on very young children education rather than on universities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年8月27日     Some jobs can pay high salaries but require employees to leave their family and friends. some jobs pay few salaries but allow employees staying with family and friend. Which job do you prefer? Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年9月18日     Agree or disagree, the rapid growth of cities has a mostly positive impact on the development of the society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年9月24日     Agree or disagree, education of children nowadays is a more difficult task because they pay attention to the cell phones, online games and social networking Web sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年9月25日     Agree or disagree, it is much easier for parents to raise children than it was 50 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年10月16日     Agree or disagree, the young people today are less dependent on their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年10月22日     Agree or disagree, famous entertainers and athletes deserve to have more privacy than they have now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年10月30日     Agree or disagree, it is the most important character of a policies or business leader to accept the responsibility of mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年11月12日     Many people nowadays spend too much money on their pets（dogs, cats, or other animals, although there are better use of this money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年11月13日     Agree or disagree, we can learn a lot about a person from his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年11月20日     Do you agree or disagree that a teacher who is serious and strict is more efficient than a teacher who uses humors and is easy going?/The most important characteristic of a successful politician or leader is good communication skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年11月26日     Agree or disagree, working at home with a computer and a phone is better than working in the company with the same staffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年12月10日     Agree or disagree, the best way to improve quality of education is to increase the teachers’ salaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年12月11日     Agree or disagree, improving schools is the most important factor in successful development of country?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2011年12月18日     Do you think government should spend money on building new houses or preserving historic buildings?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作真题" /><summary type="html">2011年1月8日     Agree or disagree, the food we ate in the past was healthier than the food today.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2015年大陆独立写作题目整理</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2015/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2015年大陆独立写作题目整理" /><published>2016-12-01T18:47:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T18:47:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2015</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2015/">&lt;p&gt;2015年1月10日     Agree or disagree: all the university students should be required to take basic science course even if it is not part of their study field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年1月11日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? The most important characteristic of a successful politician or a leader is good communication skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年1月31日     Do you agree or disagree? The rules that whole society today expects young people to follow are too strict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年2月1日     Movies and television programs have more negative effect than positive effect on the way young people behave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年3月7日     People will spend less time cooking and preparing food in twenty years than they do today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年3月7日     Some people believe that taking field trips (e.g. going to the museum) is an important part of children’s education. Others believe that it is better for children to study at school. Which view do you agree with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年3月14日     Many people nowadays spend too much money on their pets（dogs, cats, or other animals, although there are better use of this money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年3月28日     Agree or disagree, it is better to finish one project then start another than do several at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年4月12日     The internet access is as important as road building and so forth, do you think government should provide internet access to all citizens at no cost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年4月18日     Some people think we should follow our dreams, even if the dreams are ambitious. But other people think that we should focus on realistic goals. Which do you agree?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年5月9日     Should university require all the students to have history courses no matter what their fields of study are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年5月30日     When you have been friends with someone for a long time, it is important to continue friendship with the person even if he or she does something you do not like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年6月13日     It is better to spend money on traveling and vocation instead of saving it in the bank for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年6月14日     Playing sports teaches people important lessons about life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年6月27日     A friend who is intelligent is much better than a friend with a good sense of humour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年7月4日     Children will benefit in important ways through taking care of a pet animal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年7月11日     Teachers should be paid at least as much as doctors, lawyers or business leaders are paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年7月12日     Children are required to spend most of their outside of school hours on doing homework or participating organized activities related to school or sport; however, some people think children should spend time on doing what they choose to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年8月22日     Do you agree or disagree: the most effective way for governments to encourage energy conservation is to increase the price of gasoline and electricity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年8月30日     It is important to have rules about the type of clothing that people are allowed to wear at work and at school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年9月5日     If a city government wishes to attract more tourists, it can either improve its safty by hiring more police or improving its appearance by improving old buildings and streets. According to your opinion, which one is better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年9月12日     Agree or disagree, in order to succeed, you should be more like others than be different from everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年9月13日     It is as important for older people to study and learn new things as it is for younger people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年9月17日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement ? The advice from the grandparents is of no use to their grandchildren because the world has changed a lot over the past 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年9月19日     Many students now use the internet or cellphone or listening to the music when they study, do you think this is helpful or harmful for students?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年10月10日     Which schedule do you prefer, study 9 months then take a 3-month break or study 3 months then take a one -month break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年10月11日     Do you agree or disagree, it is a waste of money for government to fund space travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年10月24日     It is more important for universities to spend money on improving facilities than on hiring famous professors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年10月25日     In the past people were more friendly than they are today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年10月31日     What do you think is the most important ability for a high school teacher: a: the ability to give good advice to students about their future plan; b: the ability to recognize students who need help and help them; c: the ability to encourage students to study on their own about the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年11月8日     A school has been providing funding for students who participate in after school activities. Now the school has only enough money to fund only one type of the activities. Which of the following do you recommend the school continue to fund: sports, art, volunteering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年11月14日     Some parents can’t stay at home full time full time to care for young of preschool age. Some of these parents have the choice of sending their young children either to a child-care centre, where many children will be cared together, or to an individual caregiver, where the child will be the only one being cared for. Which approach do you think is better for a young child, and why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年11月15日     The more money people have, the more they should give away to charity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年11月21日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? The most important things people learn are from their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年11月28日     It’s more important for the government to spend money to build art museums and music performance centers than to build recreational facilities (such as swimming pool and playgrounds).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年11月29日     The quality that an effective leader must have is that they need to make decisions quickly. When leaders take too much time to make decisions they will be seen as ineffective by the people they lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年12月5日     Some people think individuals should pay for the internet while others think governments should provide people with internet for free, which one do you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年12月12日     Some companies provide important products or service, but also damage environment. Some people believe that government should require more penalty, higher tax and larger fine of these companies, while others believe there are better ways. Which do you prefer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年12月13日     Some people think that older children should take the responsibility to take care of their sisters, while others think that parents should do the whole work, which do you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年12月19日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement: the best leaders should spend more time listening to other people’s ideas than talking about his own ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015年12月20日     Out of the following three things, which one would you prefer to regulate in order to improve your health? 1）The kind of food you eat 2）The amount of exercise 3）The amount of stress in your life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作真题" /><summary type="html">2015年1月10日     Agree or disagree: all the university students should be required to take basic science course even if it is not part of their study field.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2014年大陆独立写作题目整理</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2014/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2014年大陆独立写作题目整理" /><published>2016-12-01T18:45:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T18:45:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2014</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2014/">&lt;p&gt;2014年1月12日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement ? The advice from the grandparents is of no use to their grandchildren because the world has changed a lot over the past 50 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年1月18日     In times of economic crisis, local governments often reduce the money they spend in some areas. In your opinion, if a local government is facing economic problems, which of the following areas should it spend less money on? Libraries, public transportation, or police?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年2月22日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? People who have learned many different skills are more likely to succeed than those who focus on learning only one skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年3月1日     Do you agree or disagree? It is often not a good thing for people to move to a new town or a new country because they will lose their friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年3月2日     Do you agree or disagree? The rules that whole society today expects young people to follow are too strict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年3月15日     Which way do you think is the best for a student to make new friends: a, joining a sports team; b, participating in community activities; c, travelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年3月16日     It is easier to become an educated person than it was in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年3月22日     Agree or disagree, the young people today are less dependent on their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年3月23日     It is better to have a job or vacation at least one year than to study at college at once for students who just finished high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年4月12日     Do you agree or disagree? It is more important for a university to spend money, on improving facilities(libraries, computer labs and technology in general) than to spend money on hiring famous teachers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年4月19日     For any business to be successful, it must spend more money on advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年4月27日     Your job has overall greater happiness than your social life do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年5月11日     Do you agree or disagree ? Many people spend much time on watching sports on TV. It will have negative effects on audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年5月17日     Do you agree or disagree? It’s better to relax by reading a book or watching a movie than by doing physical exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年5月24日     It is important for the government to allocate money on beautiful things, not just for things that are practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年5月25日     Parents should set strict rules if they want to help their children to be successful in the future time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年6月15日     Some prefer buy new technological devices; others having them when they are well-adopted. which do you prefer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年6月21日     Agree or disagree, people who cannot accept others’ criticism cannot achieve success as a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年6月28日     The best way to reduce air pollution is for the government to raise the cost of fuel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年6月29日     Do you think success is important, or it is more important to remain happy and optimistic when you fail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年7月6日     Do you agree that people should have hobbies and do physical activities that are very different from one’s work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年7月22日     Do you agree or disagree with the statement : Compared with people who live in cities, people who live in rural areas can take better care of families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年8月16日     The most important investment for a company to make is to spend money improving employees’ skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年8月23日A     Young people today are more likely to give time and effort to improve the world than young people were in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014/8/23 B     Although science and technology keeps advancing, most significant improvements in the quality of people’s lives have already taken place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年8月30日     The ability to maintain friendships with a small number of people over a long period for happiness is more important than the ability to make many new friends easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年9月14日     Young school children should be required to study art and music in addition to math language science and history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年9月21日     Do you agree or disagree? It is often not a good thing for people to move to a new town or a new country because they will lose their friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年9月27日A     Should university students be required to take at least one course that teaches them about the culture of a foreign country or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年9月27日B     Visiting a museum is the best way to learn about a country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年10月11日     Some agriculture methods damage the environment, but providing the food for the growing world population is important than protecting the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年10月18日     People should know about events happening around world even if they have little influence on their daily lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年10月26日     As modern life becomes more complex, itis essential for young people to have the ability to plan and organize.
2014年11月2日     People often buy the things not what they really need but what others have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年11月8日A卷     Nowadays it is important for people to have regularly family meals together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年11月8日B卷     Getting advice from friends who are older than you is more valuable than getting advice from friends of your own age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年11月9日     Which one influences you most when you make a major purchase: a) recommendations from your friends or colleagues; b) information from media (TV, newspapers, magazine); c) salesman in the market d) decide all by yourself without other information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年11月15日     Which of the following do you agree with? Parents should help children to do their work or they should encourage children to do their work independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年11月23日     Your job has overall greater happiness than your social life do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年11月29日     To record the experience, some people prefer to upload pictures and some other information on social-networking sites, some prefer not to record,which approach do you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年12月6日     Agree or disagree: Being creative, rather than planning carefully is more likely to result in the best solution to a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年12月13日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement? Students are more interested in politics today than before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年12月14日     Agree or disagree, the way of a person’s dress is an indication of his or her personality or character?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年12月21日     For a leader in student organization, honesty is the most important character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年12月27日     Young people today are more likely to help others than in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014年12月28日     It is important for the government to allocate money on beautiful things, not just for things that are practical.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作真题" /><summary type="html">2014年1月12日     Do you agree or disagree with the following statement ? The advice from the grandparents is of no use to their grandchildren because the world has changed a lot over the past 50 years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2013年大陆独立写作题目整理</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2013/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2013年大陆独立写作题目整理" /><published>2016-12-01T18:41:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-12-01T18:41:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2013</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/IW-history-2013/">&lt;p&gt;2013年1月12日     Agree or disagree, the effective leader tries to make others feel they have been part of a decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年1月13日     It is important to make sure that others know about your strengths and accomplishments; if you are not so,you will be never successful in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年1月26日     Young people nowadays are more willing to help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年1月27日     The place you choose to live has a greater effect on your happiness than your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年3月2日     Our society today is so busy and crowded that people do not need to be polite to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年3月3日     Young people today are more likely to give time and effort to improve the world than young people were in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年3月16日     Movies and TV programs made in one’s own country are more interesting than those made in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年3月17日     A leader should admit if they made a bad decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年3月22日     Though modern agricultural practices damage the environment, feeding the world’s growing population is more important than protecting against environmental damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年3月24日     Agree or disagree, it is much easier for parents to raise children than it was 50 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年3月30日     Despite the fact that many countries say they care about environmental problems, the environmental situation will not improve significantly in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年4月14日     Which contributes the most to an enjoyable vacation? Good food, good location, good friends to travel with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年4月20日     It’s more important for the government to spend money to build art museums and music performance centers than to build recreational facilities (such as swimming pool and playgrounds).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年5月11日     People often buy products not because they really need them but because other people have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年5月18日     Government should support scientific research even if the research does not have any practical use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年5月26日     The personal and work-related challenges that young people face today are not very different from the challenges their parents and grandparents faced in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年6月8日     Some students prefer to have their final grades determined by numerous small assignments, whereas others prefer to have their final grades determined by only a few large ones. Which do you prefer and why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年6月15日     Agree or disagree, the way of a person’s dress is an indication of his or her personality or character?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年6月30日     People will feel happier if they have fewer possessions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年7月13日     People rely on their neighbors less now than in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年7月14日     People were more friendly in the past than today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年7月20日     Parents now spend too much time on determining the future of their children; children should be allowed to make their own choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年7月21日     It is impossible to be completely honest with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年8月7日     Would you rather your school spend money on social events and facilities or on improving the cafeteria menus?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年8月24日     It is important to have rules about the type of clothing that people are allowed to wear at work and at school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年8月25日     It is less important to eat with families regularly nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年9月1日     Only movies that can teach us something about real life are worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年9月8日     To increase economic growth, the government should ignore the environmental concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年9月14日     People who keep their room clean and tidy are more likely to be successful in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年10月12日     Agree or disagree, in order to succeed, you should be more like others than be different from everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年10月12日     Agree or disagree, If the people move out of the native village or town is happier and more successful than the people who stay in native village or town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年10月20日     It is always better to purchase in large stores than in several small shops that specialize in different items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年10月20日     Students can use their mobile phones to surf on the internet or listen to the music while doing their homework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年10月27日     Students’ activities do as much benefit as academic study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年11月2日     A friend who is intelligent is much than a fiend with a good sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年11月9日     Parents learn more from children than children learn from parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年11月9日     Parents should spend time with their children helping them with schoolwork rather than playing games and sports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年11月17日     People can learn about a person from the books and movies the person likes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年11月23日     Teachers’ performance should be evaluated by students rather than by other teachers.
2013年11月24日     People live in countryside are happier than people live in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年12月1日     All school teachers should be required to take courses every five years to update their knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年12月7日     The government must make choices about how to spend its money on amusing the people. Given the choice between spending tax dollars on art or sports, it should choose to spend those dollars on art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年12月15日     People today do not respect their teachers as much as they did in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年12月15日     Nowadays it is easeir to maintain health than in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年12月21日     Advertising today is less honest than it was in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2013年12月28日     Should children spend most time playing and studying or they should be required to help the family with household chores, like cooking and cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作真题" /><summary type="html">2013年1月12日     Agree or disagree, the effective leader tries to make others feel they have been part of a decision.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">12月3日托福写作机经</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing-prediction-1203/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="12月3日托福写作机经" /><published>2016-11-29T11:41:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-29T11:41:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing-prediction-1203</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing-prediction-1203/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;独立写作&quot;&gt;独立写作&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;如果大家有任何问题，欢迎大家参加考前&lt;strong&gt;周四晚19：30分&lt;/strong&gt;的考前写作点题，我会带着大家一起串讲一下这些题目的思路。如果大家需要详细的答案，可以参加我们的考前机经冲刺课程。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;如果大家需要写作素材和句式，欢迎访问我们的博客：&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.yuzhoutuofu.com&quot;&gt;点我查看&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;使用方法和建议&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;机经只是我们用来跟同学们介绍方法的工具哈。我们无法保证每次机经都有原题，但是我可以保证不管考啥题目咱们的方法必然是通用的。强烈建议考前心理没啥底的同学参加一下我们的考前机经冲刺班：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.拿到机经题目的答案，包括独立写作部分的模板和示范
2.认真观看2011-2015年真题串讲视频，通过小范围机经讲方法，然后通过五年的真题约200题熟悉方法的使用。既然咱都说方法是通用得了，总得证明一下吧。哈哈。既然这么多题目看过了，考前相信大家就不会太慌乱了。祝大家好运。

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Governments should spend more money in support of the arts than in athletics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In times of economic crisis, local governments often reduce the money they spend in some areas. In your opinion, if a local government is facing economic problems, which of the following areas should it spend less money on? Libraries, public transportation, or police?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agree or disagree, improving schools is the most important factor in successful development of country?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agree or disagree, we can learn a lot about a person from his friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you agree or disagree with the following statement ? The advice from the grandparents is of no use to their grandchildren because the world has changed a lot over the past 50 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only movies that can teach us something about real life are worth watching.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some jobs pay a high salaries to employees but require them live far away from their family and friends. Some jobs pay low salary but allow employees to be closer their family and friends. Which job do prefer? And why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Movies and TV programs made in one’s own country are more interesting than those made in other countries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some people think we should follow our dreams, even if the dreams are ambitious. But other people think that we should focus on realistic goals. Which do you agree?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For future career success, the ability to relate well to other people is more important than studying hard in school.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should university students be required to take at least one course that teaches them about the culture of a foreign country or not?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agree or disagree, high school students should take some basic economy courses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The place you choose to live has a greater effect on your happiness than your job.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Agree or disagree, the best way to improve quality of education is to increase the teachers’ salaries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you agree or disagree: In order to succeed in a new job, the ability to adapt or adjust to a changing condition or circumstance is more important than having excellent knowledge of the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="写作机经" /><summary type="html">独立写作</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">11月26日托福写作考后分析</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tw-after-test-analysis-1126/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="11月26日托福写作考后分析" /><published>2016-11-29T11:41:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-29T11:41:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tw-after-test-analysis-1126</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tw-after-test-analysis-1126/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;独立写作&quot;&gt;独立写作&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;It is easier to become an educated person today than it was in the past？
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;题型：今昔对比&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;话题：教育类-接受教育的难易程度&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;思路：一边倒&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;重复：2012年11月24日 2014年3月16日 [！历年真题串讲必看！]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;一边倒&lt;/strong&gt; 本题是一个非常经典的今昔对比题目，这种题目一边倒都可以使用一样的理由，无非就是&lt;strong&gt;经济、科技、和教育&lt;/strong&gt;。经济上现在人们更有钱了，科技上网络更加发达了，而教育上我们可以说父母受教育水平提高了，这都促使现在的人比过去接受教育更加容易。当然了，我们如果套段子的话也是完全没有问题的。比如我们可以说现在的老师非常重视孩子的兴趣，因此很多孩子更愿意学习效率高学习也很开心，而过去的老师不重视，导致很多人不愿意学习；另外，现在的老师心态普遍比过去的好，因为他们知道健康的心态对于学生的影响很大；我们还可以写现在由于学生可以评价老师，老师们会更加关注学生的个体需求。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;分类讨论&lt;/strong&gt; 分类讨论其实跟一边倒只是结构不同，但针对本题来说展开的思路完全可以是一致的。今昔对比的题目我们可以按照国家和地区发展水平来分类，展开的时候我们依然可以从经济、科技、和教育三个方面对于两个地区的情况作出对比，从而得出条件好的地方确实是现在比过去接受教育更加容易，然而条件差的地方并不一定。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;兴趣的段子-记忆复写第62篇&quot;&gt;兴趣的段子 [记忆复写第62篇]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Choosing a favorite subject ensures one’s learning efficiency, allowing him to accomplish better results. According to the data analysis revealed by a research team, school students score higher in the subjects they prefer than in the subjects they dislike. Therefore, taking up their favorite subject improves performance during their course of study and brings about more satisfactory results. In a sense, excelling in a subject paves the way for a student’s academic success in the future. Conversely, if a student is forced to learn a subject not in his interest, it is difficult for him to achieve the same results, not to mention difficulty in applying it in his future career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To choose a favorite subject makes the learning experience full of joy, because happiness lies in the process, not just in the final result. To some extent, interest is a good friend making one joyful much of the time. For example, a math fanatic will receive considerable pleasure in the process of solving the math problems. Likewise, a biology enthusiast will embrace a cheerful moment after a new biology theory is grasped. Without doubt, fascination with a subject makes each step of learning delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;幽默的段子记忆复写第8篇&quot;&gt;幽默的段子[记忆复写第8篇]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Being with those who have a good sense of humor is conducive to soothing our minds whenever we feel stressed. This is because a humorous person generally owns a positive personality that naturally makes him or her skillful in tackling stressful situations. With the company of that kind of people, we will find it easy to get rid of negative feelings. I remember one of my fellow college students is this kind of friend who likes portraying teachers as cartoon characters. Under his pen, benevolent teachers became righteous ones such as Superman or Captain America, while those serious-looking teachers became Dracula or Frankenstein. His drawings brought us endless joy even in the most demanding and stressful class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;学生评价老师的段子记忆复写第14篇&quot;&gt;学生评价老师的段子[记忆复写第14篇]&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Firstly, the evaluation given by students effectively prevents teachers from neglecting student’s individual needs. Since the result of the evaluation will be closely bound up with a teacher’s bonus or promotion opportunity, teachers will be made to pay full attention to every student’s special requirements and try their best to leave a good impression on students. If this proposal were adopted, the traditional classroom would take on a new look. For example, a teacher will probably change his/her serious-looking face into a smiling and relaxing one. Or a teacher will do whatever he/she can to make the class impressive by lecturing in a humorous tone or applying multimedia technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;独立部分无非就是没思路、写不顺、写不对三个问题，没思路的一定要考前多看看历年真题串讲，多看题才能确保找思路快啊；至于写不顺或者写不对的同学，那就考前多记段子，自己写不顺、写不对就少写呗，我用别人的总不至于出问题了吧。但提醒大家，用别人的东西一定要首先记准，其次别忘了扣题，千万不要得意忘形。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;上述所有材料在考前冲刺班都有提供，大家如果考前时间比较紧，可以参加我们的冲刺班。通过模板和段子冲刺一下。模板必须搞熟，除了看示范也要自己套几个题目看看。段子要首先搞清楚思路，然后争取记住，如果记不住就把重点句式记熟，其余的东西临场发挥。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;综合写作&quot;&gt;综合写作&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;总体观点&lt;/strong&gt;
The reading is about Lascaux cave painting, painted by people living in ancient times. The reading give an image of a big horse, saying that the purpose of these cave paintings are related to hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;阅读部分&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are subject animals matters in the painting. Animals painted on the wall are extremely large, together with motifs of arrows, most of these animals are hurt, injured by such arrows perhaps.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some human images on the wall are wearing animal heads. One explanation for this is that they often disguised themselves as animals in order to catch them for food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third reason for this is that painting of animals is regarded as blessing to make their hunting successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;听力部分&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The idea in the reading is groundless, because there are still many other small animals on the wall that these ancient often did not hunt, such as cats, and still there are many animal are not injured, and no arrows on them. The major hunting target ring deer was not on the painting. Thus not necessarily related with the hunting purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It cannot be interpreted as a camouflage since it seems like they are sleeping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This represents as certain original ritual to worship the dead because they thought that the spirit of the dead were still haunting around them in terms of animal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;分析&lt;/strong&gt; 这又是一个非常经典的&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;理论证明题&lt;/code&gt;，此类题目无非就是从&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;证据本身或者从推理的角度&lt;/code&gt;来进行反驳，比如第一个点，虽然阅读的证据是对的，但它是片面的。利用片面的证据显然是不能退出正确的结论的；第二个点其实跟第一个点很类似，阅读也是利用了片面的证据，只看到人家穿什么，没看到人家的姿势。第三个稍有不同，听力没有给出新的证据，直接给出新的解释。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;综合部分大家除了练习听力之外，其实也可以多刷题，搞清楚阅读和听力的反驳关系，做多了之后猜的能力会大大加强，因为他们反驳的方式都出奇的相似，从而形成做题的感觉，大大的减少听力的压力。
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>zhanchao</name></author><category term="托福写作" /><category term="考后分析" /><summary type="html">独立写作</summary></entry></feed>
